Tom Slanda

tom.slanda@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/tomslanda | slandath.github.io

SUMMARY

As a self-motivated and dynamic professional, I have acquired extensive experience in Project Management, IT Management and Systems Integration. My strengths include exceptional communication skills, reliability and an aptitude for organization, making me an invaluable team player. Furthermore, my passion for web and software technologies has led me to become a self-taught web developer, adding to my diverse skill set.

WORK EXPERIENCE

LSPedia June 2023 - Present

IT Project Manager

Farmington Hills, MI

- Manage project execution to ensure adherence to time budget, schedule and scope
- Develop and update project plans, including deliverables, milestones, UAT and API specifications
- Assist R&D with user requirements, functional requirement specifications and integration specifications

Cello HR May 2018 - May 2023

Technology Manager

Troy, MI

- Head of daily operations for an HR technology consulting startup
- Plan, manage and lead HCM implementation projects for new clients
- Host HCM software demonstrations for leads and potential clients

The Orsus Group

September 2015 - May 2023

Technology Manager

Troy, MI

- Plan, manage and lead internal projects relating to technology and software
- Plan, manage and lead ATS, HCM and HRIS integration projects for clients
- Leveraging technology to meet organizational productivity goals
- Chosen to lead a sister company, Cello HR, in May 2018

EDUCATION

Michigan State University

Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy East Lansing, MI

CERTIFICATIONS

Meta Full-Stack Engineer Professional Certificate Google Professional Certificate in Project Management Amazon Professional Certification in AWS Fundamentals

SKILLS

Project management; agile methodology; waterfall methodology; project planning; risk mitigation; project documentation Jira; Trello; Microsoft Planner; SmartSheets; Monday.com

Front-end web development; HTML; CSS; JavaScript; Typescript; React; Bootstrap; Material UI

Back-end web development; REST API; SQL; Node.js; Express; Django; Postman;